Contact

mchischelle@aol.com

www.linkedin.com/in/michellehenderson-dnp-rn-nea-bc-cencphq-cpxp-a807b558 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Nursing Critical Care Healthcare Management

Certifications

Nurse Executive Advanced (NEA-BC)

Certified Professional in Healthcare Quality (CPHQ)

Certified Patient Experience Professional (CPXP)

CEN

Michelle Henderson DNP, RN, NEA-BC, CEN, CPHQ, CPXP

Associate Chief Nurse at Methodist Healthcare System League City, Texas

Summary

Experienced Administrator with a demonstrated history of working in the hospital & health care industry. Skilled in Healthcare Quality, Regulatory Compliance, Patient Safety and Emergency Nursing. Doctorate of Nursing Practice focused in Executive Leadership from American Sentinel University.

Experience

Methodist Healthcare System Associate Chief Nurse June 2019 - Present (1 year) San Antonio, Texas Area

UTMB HEALTHCARE SYSTEMS, INC. Administrator September 2018 - March 2019 (7 months)

Houston, Texas Area

Bay Area Regional Medical Center Chief Nursing Officer September 2016 - September 2018 (2 years 1 month)

Tomball Regional Medical Ctr Assistant Chief Nursing Officer February 2014 - September 2016 (2 years 8 months)

Tomball Regional Medical Center
Director of Emergency Services
November 2011 - February 2014 (2 years 4 months)

Paradise Valley Hospital 4 years 7 months

Director of Emergency Services August 2009 - October 2011 (2 years 3 months)

Clincal Manager, Emergency Department April 2007 - August 2009 (2 years 5 months)

Education

American Sentinel University

Doctorate of Nursing Practice, Executive · (2015 - 2017)

Grand Canyon University

Master's degree, Nursing Leadership · (2010 - 2011)

Grand Canyon University

Bachelor of Science (B.S.), Registered Nursing/Registered

Nurse · (2005 - 2007)